<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>The Holy Bible: Revised Common Version</title>
  <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com.com</link>
  <description>A modern Bible revision of a classic Bible text. The Revised Common Version (RCV) is a derivative work of Noah Webster's 1833 Common Version of the Bible (a revision of the King James Version). As with Webster's Common Version, the RCV aims to make updates to words and phrases so that they are better understood by the everyday reader who may not read the scriptures with the aid of commentaries. Care has been taken so that changes to the text are not theologically motivated, but rather are consistent with the original text. Changes include the updating of archaic words to the current equivalent, rearranging of sentences to better follow current English, adjusting of punctuation to aid the reader in the flow of reading, addition of quotation marks, notation of Old Testament quotes in the New Testament, and an outline for each chapter. Digital versions of the RCV have the words of Christ in blue.</description>
  <item>
    <title>Genesis 1:3 - Fiat Lux and Common Grace</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/fiat-lux-common-grace.html</link>
    <description>Fiat lux is a Latin phrase for, 'Let there be light.' When God created the light he established one form of his common grace. Common grace is a term used to describe the blessings God bestows upon every person on Earth, whether a believer or not...</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The RCV Needs a Wikipedia Article</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/wikipedia-article-needed.html</link>
    <description>The Revised Common Version is in need of a Wikipedia article. See article for more information.</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The RCV Project is Celebrating Its Tenth Anniversary</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/tenth-anniversary.html</link>
    <description>Ten years ago this month, back in September 2008, I officially began work on the project that would become the Revised Common Version. I had actually attempted the work two previous times, but was completely unsatisfied with the way they started that I just completely scrapped them and began anew. They say the third time is the charm, and the case was so with the RCV. Fast forward ten years and you have the project as it is today, and I must say that I am quite satisfied with how it has turned out...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Behind the RCV: Software and Utilities Used in Making the RCV Project</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/behind-the-rcv-software-and-utilities.html</link>
    <description>This article will be a little different than the other articles I have written on the RCV website. In this article I want to highlight the software and utilities I have used throughout the existence of the RCV project. There are several applications I use on the RCV project, yet they all have one thing in common: they are free and open source....</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Errata: Isaiah 11:4</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/errata-isaiah-11-4.html</link>
    <description>There is an erratum that has been addressed in the print versions of the RCV in the verse, Isaiah 11:4....</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Digital Edition of the RCV Released: r1903</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/new-digital-edition-r1903.html</link>
    <description>A new digital edition of the RCV has been released. This is the r1903 edition. This edition contains minor updates to the r1809 edition (Tenth Anniversary Edition). Edits span the entirety of the text of the RCV....</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Edition of the RCV Released: r1909</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/new-edition-r1909.html</link>
    <description>Today, I am announcing the release of a new edition of the RCV. This is the r1909 edition. This edition contains numerous updates spanning the entirety of the text of the RCV. These edits were mostly minor errata and some readability updates....</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The RCV Has an Updated Look</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/rcv-logo-update.html</link>
    <description>After 11 years of the RCV project, I have decided to give the logo a little bit of an update....</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Digital Edition of the RCV Released: r2003</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/new-digital-edition-r2003.html</link>
    <description>Today, a new digital edition of the RCV has been released. This is the r2003 edition. This edition contains minor updates that span the entirety of the text of the RCV in addition to the updated logo....</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The RCV Website Has a New Banner</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/new-website-banner.html</link>
    <description>I have had an idea for some time to update the banner area at the top of each page of the RCV website. Up until this point, the banner area has been quite minimalist. It conveyed the proper information and it scaled properly across any device that accessed the website. However, I've been wanting something that stands out just a little more and maybe introduced an element of dynamics to the RCV website. Yesterday, I had the new banner go live, and I think it accomplishes what I had wanted for the banner are of the RCV website....</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Spurgeon's Evening Devotional Added to the RCV Website</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/spurgeon-evening-devotional-added.html</link>
    <description>A new devotional has been added to the RCV website. I have included Charles Spurgeon's Evening devotional on each day's devotional reading....</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>New Formatting for the PDF File of the RCV</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/new-formatting-pdf.html</link>
    <description>I have updated the formatting of the PDF file on the Download page to look like the formatting in the print versions of the RCV found on the Purchase page. In addition to changing the formatting, the PDF has been resized to 8.5x11 inch paper....</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Psalm 151 From the Septuagint</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/psalm-151-from-septuagint.html</link>
    <description>Some time ago, I pulled my copy of the Septuagint off my bookshelf and began to peruse it. I don't recall why I was reading the Septuagint. Most likely, I was either wanting to get a different take on a passage for clarity, or I was reading an alternate translation of a passage. What caught my eye is that there was an extra bit of text after the 150th Psalm. Below is that text, which is an unofficial 151st Psalm. It wasn't numbered in my copy of the Septuagint, but I'm just going to refer to it as Psalm 151. As you read this text, try to think about one detail of the story David leaves out....</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The Extra Text of Esther from the Greek Septuagint</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/extra-text-esther-septuagint.html</link>
    <description>I can honestly say that I have never read the text of the Apocrypha. I've always been curious about it, but never took the time to read any of the text. I decided to start with the shorter works in the Apocrypha as a sort of sample of the text. One of the shorter works is some extra text found in the Story of Esther. I was immediately fascinated by this extra text in Esther as it provided more details and extended accounts of portions ofher....</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>The KJV is Available for Download</title>
    <link>https://www.revisedcommonversion.com/pages/articles/kjv-available-for-download.html</link>
    <description>I have finally made the full text of the King James Version (KJV) of the Bible available for download on the RCV website. You can find it on the Download page along with the RCV and the Webster Bible. By adding the KJV, I now have the complete English lineage of the RCV on the website....</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021</pubDate>
  </item>
  <!-- newitem -->
</channel>
</rss>
